A Finding Aid to the Ben Shahn Papers, 1879-1990, bulk 1933-1970, in the Archives of American Art AAA.shahben
Archives of American Art
- Notes and Writings, circa 1933-1988; Series 5; 1.62 Linear feet Boxes 27-28
  - Notes and Writings by Shahn, circa 1933-1986; 5.1
    - "How Art Can Contribute to an Industrial and Scientific Age," Ohio State University, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - "How to Combine Art, Architecture, Sculpture," Museum of Modern Art Symposium, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - "The Future of Creative Arts," University of New York, Buffalo, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - "Modern Art and Modern Civilization," Dartmouth College Great Issues Course, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Presentation of American Institute of Graphic Arts Award to Joe Blumenthal, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - "Question: Why Does the Artist Paint," in Philadelphia, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - "The Relationship Between Art and Aesthetics," at Woodstock, New York, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - "How an Artist Looks at Aesthetics," American Society for Aesthetics, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - "The Problem of Artistic Creation in America Today," in Philadelphia, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - "This is About Values," Smith College, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - "The Liberal of Today," and Material Related to Venice Biennale, circa 1953-1954 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Letter to Editor of New York Times re. Aline Saarinen Review of Edward Steichen Exhibition, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - "Modern American Painting," Barnard College American Arts Festival, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - "Nuove Considerazioni sul Realismo,", circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - "Realism Reconsidered," Drafts, circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - "Realism Reconsidered," Press Release, circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - "Riconsiderando il Realismo in Arte,", circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - Statements on William E. Grady Vocational High School Mural, New York, NY, circa 1956 (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - "Artists in Colleges," Harvard University, circa 1957 (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - "Nonconformity,", circa 1957 (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - "The Biography of a Painting,", circa 1957 (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - "Statement of Ben Shahn" Re: House Un-American Activities Committee, circa 1959 (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - "A Reply to Mr. Porter,", 1959 (Box 27, Folder 59)
    - "Art and Art Theory,", circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 60)
    - "My Life as a Painter,", circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 61)
    - Re: Art Critics, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 62)
    - Re: Artist's Role in Society, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 63)
    - Re: Horizons for Art, Jewish Theological Seminary, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 64)
    - Re: Modern Photography, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 65)
    - Re: Painting by a Student Named Udell, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 66)
    - "Responsibility for Standards of Taste in a Democratic Society," Museum of Modern Art Symposium, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 67)
    - Statements on Art and Artists, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 68)
    - "The Threefold Search for Understanding,", circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 69)
    - Statement to The New Republic, circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 70)
    - Re: Relationship of an Artist's Thoughts and Emotions to his Work, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 71)
    - Re: Abraham Abulafia, circa 1963 (Box 27, Folder 72)
    - Re: Corcoran Gallery of Art Awards System, circa 1963 (Box 27, Folder 73)
    - "Bread and Butter Letter to the Aspen Conference on Design,", 1967 (Box 27, Folder 74)
  - Writings by Others, About Shahn, circa 1950s-1988; 5.2
    This series is arranged alphabetically by author and has been scanned in entirety.
    - Braunstein or Pieri, Diane (author unclear), "Ben Shahn's Social Commentary,", circa 1960s (Box 27, Folder 75)
    - Friendly, Fred W., Remarks for Art Directors Club Hall of Fame Dinner, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 76)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, "Ben Shahn,", circa 1969 (Box 27, Folder 77)
    - O'Neal, Hank, "A Vision Shared,", circa 1976 (Box 27, Folder 78)
    - Shahn, Bernarda Bryson, Book Manuscript, circa 1972; 4 Folders (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
    - Shahn, Bernarda Bryson, Essays and Fragments, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Soby, James Thrall, Re: The Graphic Art of Ben Shahn, circa 1957 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Volpo, Marisa? "Gli Artisti nelle Universita,", circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified Authors (Box 28)
      - Alleged Associations with Communism, circa 1965 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - "Ben Shahn and Joyce,", 1960 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "Ben Shahn and People,", 1950 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - "Four American Graphic Designers", circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - "Mr. Ben Shahn,", circa 1950-1960 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - "Through Ben Shahn's Eyes,", circa 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - "With Cut-Away Eyelids,", circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - Untitled and Fragments, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Writings by Others, Not Shahn-Related, 1935-1966; 5.3
    Writings found here, primarily in the form of transcripts, are on subjects of interest to Shahn many of which were presumably used as source material for his artwork, sparked his interest in a particular commission such as those by John Barlow Martin, or were given to him as possible commissions for illustrations.
    This series is arranged alphabetically by author with details provided in the index. The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of the full text of some writings.
    List of Writings from Series 5.3
    Writings are listed alphabetically by author; writings by unidentifed authors appear at the end of the list.
    Barr, Alfred: "The United States at the Venice Biennale," 1954
    Bernstein, Aline: "Battle Hymn"
    Block, Lou: "Ballyhoo vs. Information," circa 1943
    Brennan, Francis: "The Picture and the Word," 1956
    Brennan, Francis: Account of trip to Russia, 1960
    Brennan, Francis: Speech for Conference of Western Association of Art Museums
    Dugan, Alan: "Society of the Free and Easy"
    Dugan, Alan: "Speech to the N.B.A"
    Durr, Clifford J.: "The Trial of Jesus as a Loyalty Hearing"
    Dye, Joan: "Juvenile Delinquency," 1956
    Endore, Guy: "Address to the School of Library Science, UCLA," 1962
    Engel, Monroe: "A Father's Geography," 1956
    Ferry, W. H.: "Black Colonies: A Final Solution"
    Ferry, W. H.: Address from the Western States Democratic Conference
    Ferry, W. H.: "Why the College is Failing," 1963
    Ferry, W. H.: "A Proposal from Ralph Helstein, Robert Theobald, and W. H. Ferry," 1963
    Ferry, W. H.: "The Triple Revolution: An Appraisal of the Major U. S. Crises and Proposals for Action," 1964
    Ferry, W. H.: "The Muddle in Education," 1964
    Fielder, Leslie A.: "Nude Croquet"
    Fuller, R. Buckminster: Letter to Mr. Higman, Conference on World Affairs, University of Colorado, 1963
    Goldburg, Rabbi Robert: Memorial prayer for John F. Kennedy, 1963
    Goldin, Judah: Translation of "The Grace After Meals"
    Gregory, Horace: "Alphabet for Joanna"
    "Vincent Van Gogh's 'Landscapes of the Soul'"
    Gusten, Theodore: "Vincent Van Gogh, We and Picasso"
    Johnson, Lyndon B.: Excerpts from Address to National Education Association, 1965
    Joyce, Robert: "The Working Artist," 1961
    Kacmarcik, Frank: "The Bible and Creative Imagination"
    Kastner, Frank: "The Bible and Creative Imagination"
    Kennedy, John F.: Statements, 1963
    Lamont, Corliss: Statement before the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigation, 1953
    Langum, John K: "Prospects for the American Economy," 1965
    Lemon, Richard: "Campaign Song"
    Levinson, Alfred: "Cricket in the Mill"
    Lewis, Margery: "The Young American Artist"
    Martin, John Bartlow: "The Mecca Building"
    Martin, John Bartlow: "The Hickman Story"
    Martin, John Bartlow: "A Letter About Upper Michigan"
    Martin, John Bartlow: "A Trip to the Lincoln Country"
    Piel, Gerard: "Science, Disarmament and Peace," 1958
    Pines, David, editor: Statement about book "Frontiers in Physics"
    Pollack, Peter: Statement on establishment of the National Arts Foundation and the National Council on the Arts, 1963
    Reid, Alistair: "A Spelling for Sleeping"
    Reid, Alistair: "A Lesson in Music"
    Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff: "Will the Creative Arts Thrive or Degenerate During the Next Fifty Years?"
    Rodman, Selden: "Death of the Hero: A Modern Morality"
    Rodman, Selden: Reviews
    Roosevelt, Franklin Delano: Addresses to Congress, 1942
    Rosenblum, William F.: Script of Chanukah pageant and story, 1962
    Rosskam, Edwin: "Three Victims," 1960s
    Rosten, Lou: "Gandhi," 1964
    Roth, Cecil: "Had Gadya," 1965
    W.H.S.: "What Price Peace?" 1963
    Schlesinger, Jr., Arthur: "Government and the Arts," 1962
    Shyre, Paul: "The Child Buyer" Play script adapted from novel by John Hershey
    Taylor, Harold: "The First Sex: or Oedipus Unbound," 1953
    Terracini, Umberto: Preface for "The Jews of the USSR," 1966
    Tyler, Parker: Review of Exhibition by Henri Cartier-Bresson, Walker Evans and M. Alvarez Bravo, 1935
    Wilder, Thornton: Playscript, "The Seven Deadly Sins - Number Six: Lust/Someone from Assisi"
    Wilder, Thornton: Playscript, "The Seven Ages of Man - Number One: Infancy"
    Wilder, Thornton: Playscript, "Childhood"
    Yeats, W. B: Playscript: "Calvary" with production notes from Theatre Intime production
    "Project by the Brooklyn Museum for a Major Exhibition of Photographs Dealing with Puerto Rico and Puerto Ricans"
    "The Use of Earle Browder's Image in a Mural"
    Mr. Passow's Proposals Concerning Childhood Talent," 1966
    "Problems Connected with Education in the Fine and the Applied Arts"
    Possible chapters for a book: "Entertaining Notions" and "In the Name of Art"
    "How to...Anything"
    "New Forms vs. Reforms"
    "The Transformation of the Novel"
    "A Proposal to Establish a New and Permanent Opera Group in Boston"
    "For Michael's Sake"
    "Mino Maccari"
    "The Sacco and Vanzetti Case"
    "You the Steel Worker"
    "Steel Strike in Warren, Ohio"
    "Towards a Rural Housing Program"
    "First Draft of Resettlement Administration Primer"
    "Proposal for a Rural Community Center Program"
    "Designing Museum Buildings"
    "Food for Thought - A Creative Menu"
    "The Dustbowl"
    "President's Committee on Farm Tenancy," 1937
    "God"
    "A Portrait of the Plasma as a Many-Body Problem"
    "Story About Kay-Kay"
    "The Short Grace After Meals"
    Text for a Woman's Pamphlet
    "Metropolitan Museum"
    See index for list of writings.
    - Amherst Junior High School Special Class, circa 1950s (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - B: Barr - Brennan, circa 1943-circa 1960 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Conklin, Groff, Translation of "The Dolorous Chatelaine,", 1953 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      translation has not been scanned
    - D: Dugan - Dye, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - E: Endore - Engel, 1956, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Ferry, W. Hawkins, 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - F: Fielder - Fuller, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - G: Goldburg - Gusten, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - J: Johnson - Joyce, 1961-1965 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - K: Kacmarak - Kennedy, circa 1939-1963 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - L: Lamont - Lewis, circa 1953-circa 1965 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Martin, John Bartlow, circa 1948 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - P: Piel - Pollack, circa 1958-1963 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - R: Reid - Roth, 1942-1965 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Shahn, Abigail, Notebook, circa 1950s (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - S: W.H.S. - Shyre, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - T: Taylor - Tyler, 1935-1966 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      text of "The Child Buyer" has not been scanned
    - Wilder, Thornton, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Yeats, W. B., Playscript: Calvary, with Production Notes from Theatre Intime Producction, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Unidentified Authors, circa 1930s-circa 1960s; 4 Folders (Box 28, Folder 35-38)
    - Unidentified Authors, Fragments and Untitled, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified Authors, Poems, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Various Authors, Poems, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Various Authors, Poems About Sports ("Field Day" compilation), circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Various Authors, Unidentified Panel Abstracts by S. V. Martorana, Brenda Sexton and Herbert Goldstein, circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 43)
- Artwork, circa 1930s-1965; Series 6; 11 Folders Boxes 28, 35
  This small series contains several sketches by Shahn in addition to artwork by others including childhood drawings of his children, Ezra and Judith, and prints by friends including Mario Casetta and Stefan Martin. Unbound sketches by Shahn include what is probably an original drawing of Shahn's childhood friend, Willie Snow, circa 1910-1920.
  Artwork by Shahn is followed by artwork by others, arranged alphabetically by artist. This series has been scanned in entirety.
  - Shahn, Ben, Sketchbook, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Shahn, Ben, Unbound Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1963 (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Appel, Willa, Drawing and Tempera Painting, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Casetta, Mario, Prints, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 47)
  - Hanisch, Helen, Ink Sketch of Shahn, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Martin, Stefan, Print, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Shahn, Ezra, Childhood Drawings, circa 1930s (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Shahn, Judith, Childhood and Other Drawings, circa 1930s-circa 1940s (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - Thomas, Drawing, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - Unidentified Artists and Children, Drawings and Sketches, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Unidentified Artists, Prints, circa 1950s (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Oversized Material from Casetta, Mario, Prints, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 28, F47
  - Oversized Material from Hanisch, Helen, Ink Sketch of Shahn, 1965 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 28, F48
  - Oversized Material from Shahn, Judith, Childhood and Other Drawings, circa 1930s-circa 1940s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 28, F51
  - Oversized Material from Unidentified Artists and Children, Drawings and Sketches, circa 1940s-circa 1960s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 38, F53
- Source Files, circa 1900s-1960s; Series 7; 1.81 Linear feet Boxes 28-30, 35
  Source files contain printed material, primarily newspaper clippings, and photographs relating to topics depicted by Shahn in his artwork, including children, dust, farming, houses, mines and miners, slums, war and workers.
  Of particular note are the file for "Children" which includes one of the clippings Shahn used as a source for Girl Skipping Rope (1943); scattered photographic prints by FSA and OWI photographers including Shahn and Jack Delano, Walker Evans, Dorothea Lange, Russell Lee, Carl Mydans, Marion Post Wolcott, Arthur Rothstein, and John Vachon; files for "Steel Country," which include prints of photographs taken by Shahn on his 1938 assignment to Ohio as a photographer for the Historical Section of the Resettlement Administration; and a group of photographs of Louis Armstrong's 1956 visit to the Gold Coast.
  Files are arranged alphabetically by subject. The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of large groups of news clippings.
  - Aluminum, circa 1930s-circa 1940s (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Armstrong, Louis, 1956; 5 Folders (Box 28, Folder 56-60)
  - Art, circa 1930s-circa 1940s; 4 Folders (Box 28, Folder 61-64)
    (includes original drawing by H. Cross and an unidentifed sketch)
  - Beach and Carnival, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Bonus Fight, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Book Burning, circa 1930s (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Campaign 1944, 1936-1944; 8 Folders (Box 29, Folder 4-11)
    (F10 includes photo of Shahn; includes CIO-PAC photos)
  - Cattle, circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Children, 1934-1950 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    (includes one of the news clippings Shahn used as a source for Girl Skipping Rope, 1943)
  - Church, 1932-1939 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Congressman, 1937-1944 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Conventions, 1934-1948 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Dams, 1936-1944 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Defeated Germans and Japanese, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Dust, 1934-1938 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Edison, Thomas A., 1920s (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Execution, circa 1930s (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Farm Labor, circa 1909-1942 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Farm Strike, circa 1933 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Farming, 1930s-circa 1940s; 6 Folders (Box 29, Folder 24-29)
    (includes many photographs used by Shahn for a pamphlet he designed for the Office of War Information, circa 1942)
  - Fascism, circa 1941 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Fire, circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Flood, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Folk Art, circa 1940 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Freud, Sigmund, circa 1930s-circa 1950s (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Ga-Ga, circa 1930s-circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Grief, circa 1930s (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Hillman, Sidney, 1940-1944 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Hitler, Adolf, circa 1938 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - House Builders, circa 1930s (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Houses, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Industry, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Jews, 1930s-1950s (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Kelly, Charles (Medal of Honor recipient), 1944 (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Korean War, 1950-1952 (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - Labor, 1930s-1940s; 3 Folders (Box 29, Folder 45-47)
  - Lynching of Thomas Thurmond and John Holmes, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - May Day, 1932-1934 (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - McCarthy, Joseph, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - Mecca, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - Mines and Miners, 1930s-1940s; 4 Folders (Box 29, Folder 52-55)
  - Mooney, Thomas J., 1919-1932; 5 Folders (Box 29, Folder 56-60)
  - Movie Stars, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 61)
  - Murder, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 62)
  - Music, circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 63)
  - Negroes, 1930s-1960s; 2 Folders (Box 29, Folder 64-65)
  - Parks, 1930s; 2 Folders (Box 29, Folder 66-67)
  - People Alone, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 68)
  - People Together, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 69)
  - Portraits, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 70)
  - Post Office, circa 1900s-circa 1930s (Box 29, Folder 71)
  - Punishment, 1930s-1950s (Box 29, Folder 72)
  - Refugees, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 73)
  - Roadside Signs, circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 74)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 75)
  - Ruin, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 76)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, circa 1940s (Box 29, Folder 77)
  - Sailors, circa 1940s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Science, 1930s-1950 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Scottsboro, 1932-1933; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Seasons, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Shipbuilding, 1940s; 6 Folders (Box 30, Folder 7-12)
  - Sick, 1941-1950 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Slavery, 1930s (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Slums, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Sports, 1930s-1950s (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Steel Country, 1938; 4 Folders (Box 30, Folder 17-20)
  - Strikes and Police, 1930s-1950s; 3 Folders (Box 30, Folder 21-23)
    folder 23 has not been scanned
  - Top Hat, 1920s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Truman, Harry S., circa 1945 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Umbrellas, circa 1930s (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Unemployment, 1920s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Victory, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - War, circa 1918-1940s; 6 Folders (Box 30, Folder 29-34)
    folder 30 has not been scanned
  - War Materials, 1940s (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - War Workers, 1940s-1950 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Washington, D.C., circa 1940s (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - Weddings, circa 1930s (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - Women, 1930s (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - Women in Politics, circa 1940s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 40-41)
  - Work, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - Workers, 1930s-1940s; 2 Folders (Box 30, Folder 43-44)
  - Oversized Material from Campaign, 1944 (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 29, F5
  - Oversized Material from War, circa 1918-1940s (Box 35)
    oversized material scanned with Box 30, F34
- Printed Material, 1912-1988; Series 8; 3.22 Linear feet Boxes 30-33, 35, OV 39
  Printed material includes exhibition announcements and catalogs for many Shahn exhibitions, dating from some of his earliest shows at the Downtown Gallery including The Passion of Sacco and Vanzetti in 1932. A large portion of the series consists of clippings and articles from newspapers and other publications documenting events in Shahn's career. Scattered reprints of essays written by Shahn are found here, as well as scattered articles illustrated by Shahn such as John Barlow Martin's "The Blast in Centralia No. 5," published in Harper's in 1948. One item of particular note in Clippings is a copy of the publication the Jewish Daily Forward, from April 1936. There are also 14 issues, and a paste-up layout of the 1930s publication Art Front.
  In addition to clippings about Shahn, Clippings Reference Files contains primarily photographs from newspapers on a wide range of political and human interest subjects.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned; only representative samples of large groups of clippings have been scanned and typically only the covers and relevant pages of publications have been scanned.
  - Art Front Magazine, 1934-1935 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - Art Front Magazine, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Art Front Magazine, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Art Front, Paste-up Layout for Magazine, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - Brochures for Artwork, 1955-1965 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - Brochures for Equipment and Supplies, undated (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - Brochures for Events, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 30, Folder 51)
  - Brochures for Events, 1949-1959 (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - Brochures for Events, 1961-1964 (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - Brochures for Events, 1965-1972 (Box 30, Folder 54)
  - Brochures for Organizations, circa 1952-circa 1963 (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - Brochures for Publications, 1955-1964 (Box 30, Folder 56)
  - Brochures for Schools, 1955-1979 (Box 30, Folder 57)
  - Brochures, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 30, Folder 58)
  - Catalogs, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 30, Folder 59)
  - Clippings, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; 3 Folders (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
  - Clippings, 1932-1934 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1935; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 5-6)
  - Clippings, 1936-1945 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    oversized material housed in OV 40
  - Clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1953; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1956; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
  - Clippings, 1957; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 19-20)
  - Clippings, 1958; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 21-22)
  - Clippings, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1960; 2 Folders (Box 31, Folder 24-25)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1962; 3 Folders (Box 31, Folder 27-29)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1965-1969 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1970-1988 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Clippings Reference Files, circa 1920s-circa 1940s; 7 Folders (Box 31, Folder 34-40)
    bulk not scanned
  - Clippings Reference Files, circa 1932-1933 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Clippings Reference Files, circa 1934-1937 (Box 31, Folder 42)